export const mcqs = [
    {
        id: 'q1',
        question: "Underlying contract for savings accounts in Islamic banking is;",
        options: ["Qarz", "Mudarabah", "Shariat", "Profit Sharing ratio"],
        correctAnswer: "Mudarabah"
    },
    {
        id: 'q2',
        question: "In Mudarabah the profit calculation mechanism is called __________________.",
        options: ["Weightages", "Profit payment option", "Cost of fund"],
        correctAnswer: "Weightages"
    },
    {
        id: 'q3',
        question: "The sources of Shari’ah are;",
        options: ["two", "three", "four", "five"],
        correctAnswer: "four"
    },
    {
        id: 'q4',
        question: "The word Rab ul Maal refer to the investing partner in a contract of ________",
        options: ["leasing", "trading", "partnership (Mudarabah)"],
        correctAnswer: "partnership (Mudarabah)"
    },
    {
        id: 'q5',
        question: "Underlying contract for current account in Islamic Banking is called;",
        options: ["Mudarabah", "Salam", "Qarz", "Partnership"],
        correctAnswer: "Qarz"
    },
    {
        id: 'q6',
        question: "If a business wants to avail financing for purchase of land we can use the contract of _______",
        options: ["Diminishing Musharakah", "Salam", "Murabaha"],
        correctAnswer: "Diminishing Musharakah"
    },
    {
        id: 'q7',
        question: "Basic requirements for a valid sale include the following except",
        options: ["Price", "Possession", "Subject Matter", "Season"],
        correctAnswer: "Possession"
    },
    {
        id: 'q8',
        question: "Ijarah refers to transferring the____________ of an asset but not its______________.",
        options: ["1. Usage , 2. ownership", "1. ownership, 2. usufruct"],
        correctAnswer: "1. Usage , 2. ownership"
    },
    {
        id: 'q9',
        question: "Ijarah is also used for ______;",
        options: ["Long Term Financing", "Saving Account", "Investment agency"],
        correctAnswer: "Long Term Financing"
    },
    {
        id: 'q10',
        question: "Islamic bank’s saving account is based on;",
        options: ["Mudaraba", "Qardh", "Amanah"],
        correctAnswer: "Mudaraba"
    }
];

export const trueFalseQuestions = [
    {
        id: 'tf1',
        question: "Any type of gain in a contract of loan is called Riba",
        correctAnswer: "True"
    },
    {
        id: 'tf2',
        question: "In case of Mudarabah if there is a loss, it will be shared by the members of the Pool in ratio of their investment",
        correctAnswer: "True"
    },
    {
        id: 'tf3',
        question: "Weightages are assigned based on: (1) Investment tenure (2) Profit payment option (3) Amount tiers (4) Product Features (5) Market Conditions",
        correctAnswer: "True"
    },
    {
        id: 'tf4',
        question: "Al-Bai is used to provide finance only on manufactured goods;",
        correctAnswer: "False"
    },
    {
        id: 'tf5',
        question: "In Qarz contract, the deposit amount is guaranteed to the depositor, where as the principal amount is not guaranteed in Mudarabah contract.",
        correctAnswer: "True"
    },
    {
        id: 'tf6',
        question: "An Istisna Agreement is an order to manufacture, where bank orders its customer to make goods. The same goods are then sold by Bank (through the customer) to ultimate buyers.",
        correctAnswer: "True"
    },
    {
        id: 'tf7',
        question: "Anything which can be used without being consumed can be rented out (eg. Shop, house, machinery etc).",
        correctAnswer: "False"
    },
    {
        id: 'tf8',
        question: "Diminishing Musharakah (DM) is a partnership transaction in which the partners agree to reduce share of one partner gradually.",
        correctAnswer: "True"
    },
    {
        id: 'tf9',
        question: "Working Capital Musharakah is an alternative to conventional Working Finance",
        correctAnswer: "True"
    },
    {
        id: 'tf10',
        question: "Salam can be used for homogeneous goods.",
        correctAnswer: "True"
    }
];
